IBRAHIM BALOGUN

House 14, Johnson Adetoye Drive Andikan Beulah Estate, Gwarinpa II, Abuja Nigeria | Tel: +(234)706 186 6475

Email: mololuwa.ibrahim@gmail.com | Portfolio: https://ibrahim-portfolio-77nl.onrender.com

SUMMARY

Experienced and adaptable IT professional with over 8 years of experience, including 4 years as a software developer. Recognized for developing cost-saving software applications and awarded "Employee of the Year" in 2017. Strong proficiency in web development using Python (Flask and Django), JavaScript, HTML5, and CSS, with a proven track record in digital transitions.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Sept 2012 - Ongoing IT Support Analyst Joint Admissions and Matriculation Board (JAMB) FCT Abuja, Nigeria

- Designed and maintained a web application for the JAMB INSAAF COOPERATIVE project, demonstrating expertise in web architecture and database management.
- Designed and maintained a web application for the INTIMENG project, demonstrating expertise in web architecture and database management.
- Designed and maintained a web application for the Central Admissions Processing System (CAPS) project, demonstrating expertise in web architecture and database management.
- Integrated data from 725 higher institutions into a centralized system, showcasing organizational and multitasking skills.
- Provided technical support for JAMB examinations internationally and locally, demonstrating adaptability.

Jan 2011 - Dec 2012 IT Expert FCT Archives and History Bureau FCT Abuja, Nigeria

- Monitored and maintained the agency's local area network, file server, and security surveillance system, highlighting strong technical support skills.
- Managed relationships with local vendors for IT services, showcasing communication and negotiation skills.

EDUCATIONS

June 2014 - Dec 2019 BSC Degree Economics University of Abuja FCT Abuja, Nigeria

PROJECTS

Project: INSAAF Cooprative, Intimeng and locally deployed web apps such as, help line form app, office managment app, taxis in Nasarawa among others

• Developed web applications using Python, JavaScript, HTML5, and CSS with the Flask and Django framework. An app for contributions loan and investment for members. And intimeng is an app for logistics https://jmcs-insaaf.onrender.com, https://intimeng.onrender.com with deployment using Nginx and Gunicorn.

ALX Team Project: AirBnB Clone

- Developed web applications using Python, JavaScript, HTML5, and CSS with the Flask framework.
- Contributed to the AirBnB Clone v1, v2, v3, v4 projects. GitHub: github.com/IbroDante/AirBnB_clone_v4
- Managed web applications using Python, JavaScript, HTML5, and CSS with the Flask framework. EduNg: An app for
 educational studies and material sharing between students. https://github.com/IbroDante/EduNg.git, with deployment

using Nginx and Gunicorn.

RELEVANT SKILLS

- Programming Languages: Python (Flask and Django), JavaScript, Node.js
- Web Technologies: HTML5, CSS, MySQL
- DevOps and Tools: Git, GitHub, Load Balancing, Web server, Application server
- Operating Systems: Linux, Mac, Windows
- Technical Support: User Support Technician, Network Administrator, Desktop Support

LANGUAGES

English

PROFESSIONAL CERTIFICATIONS

- African Leadership Programme (ALX) Software Engineer 2022 2024
- Modern Technology in ICT (Training) Newcastle University, United Kingdom 2014 Customer Care/Servicom Certificate (Training) 2019
- Item Banking/IRT Training in CITO Arnhem The Netherland 2012 and 2014

JOB-SPECIFIC SKILLS

- HTML, JavaScript, CSS, MySQL
- · MS Office, Python
- Experience in leading and coordinating multidisciplinary teams.
- Personal Suitability: Client focus, Dependability, Initiative, Judgment, Organized, Team player

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

- Basic security clearance
- · Able to work under pressure